That sound you hear is billionaires
heading off to Tidor airport to evacuate
city due to the socialist uprising of
Zaran Mamani. Thanks for tuning in to
Drogram with Ted R and John Kiryaku.
Good morning, John.
>> Good morning, Ted. Lots to talk about
today.
>> Yeah, a few things. It's Wednesday,
November 5th, 2025. Zon Mandani. Um, by
the way, I just want to say that here on
the show,
>> we nailed his victory. The numbers, uh,
we said 52.
>> Yeah, we did.
>> 51.5 is the current count. So, uh, we,
you know, I mean, kudos to us.
>> You don't like the show, you should
probably refer to us if you're an online
better.
>> Seriously, we called it.
>> Yeah,
>> we called it. Yeah,
>> we called it everywhere. And you know,
this was this was not just kind of an
interesting
off-year election. Um,
this was a uh landslide nationwide. Uh,
if you look, for example, at uh
Virginia, the Democrats picked up 10
state house seats. They already
controlled the state house. They picked
up 10 more. Three are still close too
close to call. All held by Republicans.
They could pick up as many as 13. In
Pennsylvania,
uh there were three elections for um
state supreme court. There the Supreme
Court justices in Pennsylvania are
elected to 10-year terms. Democrats won
every seat. So, the Democrats now
control the Supreme Court of um of
Pennsylvania, one of the important
battleground states. Uh last year we saw
uh a Democrat win the deciding Supreme
Court seat in Wisconsin. So, this is
happening uh in California
where Republicans spent $100
million
to try to defeat this referendum calling
for redistricting so that the Democrats
could try to offset some of the
Republican redistricting efforts in
Florida, Texas, Ohio, North Carolina,
Indiana, and Missouri.
63.8%
8%
supported redistricting. That was a
monumental landslide. I'll tell you, if
if I were the Republicans, I would be
gravely worried today. But with that
said,
you cannot run
with your sole campaign slogan being,
"Vote for me because I'm not the other
guy." The Democrats have to come up with
ideas. And so far, they have no ideas. I
will say I've taken I've taken a couple
of swipes at Abby uh Spanberger
and I mentioned yesterday Abby and I
worked together in the CIA's
counterterrorism center. Um
she ran as a
moderate a right of center uh Democrat,
a conservative Democrat. Mhm.
>> Um
but then in her postelection victory
speech last night, she said all the
right things. And man, I hope for the
sake of having a viable Democratic party
that they listen to what she said. She
said she is going to immediately sponsor
constitutional amendments
to guarantee a woman's right to an
abortion.
Um, she's going to
There was another constitutional
amendment that it was like going to the
very Oh. Oh. to to recognize in
perpetuity same-sex marriages.
And her first bill that she's going to
uh propose to the legislature is to
guarantee
um a $15 minimum wage, plus paid uh uh
leave for women who have just had uh
children, parental leave, whatever it's
called.
None of which has ever been done in
Virginia before. And um and there's
going to be something about
I forget what handgun registration or
something like that which will probably
fail. But anyway, real ideas for a
change instead of oh vote for me because
I'm not Donald Trump. Now much to the
Republican chagrin today in Virginia,
state senator Jay Jones uh defeated the
heavily favored Republican attorney
general Jason Mures. Um Jay Jones on
October the 22nd, which was what, less
than two weeks ago,
um somebody leaked text messages that he
had sent to a friend in 2022 talking
about shooting Republicans in the head.
Now, of course, this is something
Republicans have done time and time
again, but this time, of course, they
completely lose their [__] because a
Democrat did it. And nobody cared.
Everybody said, "Oh, there's going to be
a lot of ticket splitting. People are
gonna vote for Abby and then they're
going to vote for Miis, the Republican
attorney general." That didn't happen.
Miis has been a terrific attorney
general.
And and it's it's hard for me to say
that about a conservative Republican,
but he has been an excellent attorney
general. And he was just unceremoniously
thrown out last night um for uh for Jay
Jones. Now, we'll see what Jay Jones
does in this position.
>> I mean, John, have you ever seen a a a
one party sweep in not even an off-year
election, but an off offyear election
like this? I can't remember one. I mean,
not like you can't really you can't
really read a lot of tea leaves out of a
election like this. There was even a
Republican a Republican in
Fredericksburg, Virginia, which is, you
know, it's an old South kind of, you
know, Civil War era, pre- Civil War era
town. Very, very Republican. Their state
representative was elected in 1988.
>> And he lost last night to a 20-some year
old Democrat.
>> So 1988, Ted,
>> but if I'm Look, I agree with you. 100
million% John about this Democrats have
to have an idea besides Trump sucks.
What we're seeing I think this is just
something Democrats should not take a
lot of comfort in. What we're seeing is
every election now is a change election
because Americans are pissed across the
board for different reasons. They're all
pissed. And so two-party system, they're
just going to keep flailing and voting
against the incumbents over
>> That's it. And that's bad for the
country. We need
we need real ideas. People who are going
to stand up for something, not just
pandering so that they can get elected
next time. That's exactly what's wrong
with this country.
>> Totally. John, got to read an ad. Did
you know the biggest threat to your
retirement is not something that's
talked about often? Our increased
longevity in America means default
retirement accounts like IAS, 401ks, and
TSPs may not suffice. If you ever have
over $100,000 in your retirement
account, get instant access to a free
two-day rep two minute report, sorry,
from Augusta Precious Metals that
reveals the one step you can take to
secure your financial future. Text safe
to 35052
today. 35052.
>> Good. Little housekeeping too about uh
you know, just want to encourage people.
Just a reminder, we're trying to get our
producer back, Robbie West, who got
doxed and uh is uh leaving his job to
come work for us full-time. Um we need
your support to help do that. John and I
are each going to be uh digging uh
shaking out the the the sofa cushions to
pay out of our own pockets, but it's not
going to be enough. So if we want this
show to work and you want Robbie to help
us make it succeed. So he, you know, he
behind the scenes he creates clips, he
promotes it, he does metadata,
he u prom he he he he works with Rumble
when there's a problem um you know with
our pay or whatever. He's the guy who
handles all the tech stuff behind. Uh
we're calling it Robbie Aid. Uh please
reach out directly and send the money to
him. We're asking for $1,000 a month
total from across the big world. So, um
that we feel like that's not asking too
much, but we'll see. Um the URL is
giveendgo.comwestglacaming.
I'll leave the URL up there. Um this is
a uh you know, we got it. Uh first of
all I just want to say you know we kept
saying you know to about billionaires
like uh the Gustidis grocery guy with
the long name
>> John John Katy Matis.
>> Uh that's easy for you to say.
>> So long John.
>> Yeah. You you Yeah. You're all you're
all afraid of New York. Like this
morning on um on my Facebook feed uh a
lot of my Zionist friends are saying you
know oh you know like New York we hardly
knew ye. Uh my right-wing uh friends on
X are posting images of a plane hitting
the World Trade Center and saying, "How
could you have voted for a Muslim after
what happened?"
>> Yeah. Because he did it. He did 911.
>> If you guys are genuinely this scared,
then you need to leave. Yeah.
>> Or you need And if you join the
military,
>> you need to be quiet because you're full
of [__] Yeah.
>> Because one, if you're really that
scared, you shouldn't stick around. New
Jersey will be happy to have you. Oh,
wait. They became they they went
Democratic. Oh. Uh, Pennsylvania will be
happy to have you. Oh, wait. They went
Democratic. Keep going. Go to Ohio. Hang
out with JD Vance when he's not making
out with the widow.
>> Yes, exactly.
>> Hey, do you mind if I answer a couple of
questions? Please, let's do it. Um, one
is, um, what's my reaction to John
Brennan's interaction with Thomas Bial
at George Mason University on the 30th?
I'm not exaggerating when I tell you at
least a dozen friends of mine sent sent
me the video
and um, and I watched it at least a half
a dozen times with Brennan physically
poking him in the chest, which by the
way is assault,
>> but that's beside the point. I've known
John Brennan for 35 years.
That's the first time I've ever seen him
scared.
I think he's genuinely scared of what's
going to happen to him. You know, the
the drain is open and I think the water
is starting to uh to circle.
So, uh yeah, I'm glad I'm not John
Brennan today. Somebody also asked me if
I had seen the mass shooting in Cree,
the Greek island of Cree. And I'm
smiling because
being Greek, being Greek,
every Greek knows about Cree.
Everybody's armed and everybody's pissed
off at somebody else. It's just the
nature of being [__] [laughter] It's
like they're like Sicilians. Very much
like Sicilians.
In fact, it was the ancient
>> course. That's how Corsicans are in
France. Yes, that's right. That's how
corsans are. It's the same thing. If you
look at me crosseyed or you insulted my
sister or you cut my dad off in traffic
and didn't say you're sorry, blood feud
and it'll go for generations. So, what
happened was one of these feuds bubbled
over and um guy started shooting and
killed a whole bunch of people from the
other family. So, it's not a terrorist
attack. It's just cretins being cretins.
And even the prime minister, who is
[__] by the way, he's like, "Look, we
have to stop this this silliness. Every
time you get mad, you just go get your
hundred-year-old Ottoman rifle and start
shooting people you don't like. You
can't do that."
One other question from Nicholas Franco.
Uh, John, why is it that we cannot
pronounce the name of the red-headed
devil, although her name is out there?
Um,
you know, I I got burned thanks to the
uh the Intelligence Identities
Protection Act of 1982. So, I don't
pronounce her name because I don't say
her name. I don't say her name because I
don't think she deserves the uh
>> the media attention.
>> She who must not be named. Uh she's a
war criminal. She's a genocidal, you
know, example of everything that is
wrong with the CIA. Uh,
her name is out there.
>> Yeah, I know who you
>> I I just don't want to say it.
>> No need. No need at all.
>> But sorry, I didn't mean to pull us off
of politics, Ted.
>> No, no, that's quite all right. Listen,
um, I suspect chainery. Um, not in the
Mandani win, but do you really believe
that Andrew Cuomo did as well as they
claim?
>> No.
>> And that and and and that Curtis Leewa
did as poorly. No, I do not. I do not.
And listen, I don't care how
conservative Staten Island is. I don't
think he won Staten Island as big as
everybody says he did.
>> That's That's Curtis Leewa territory.
>> Yeah, it's Curtis Leewa territory.
They're all Republicans on Staten
Island. Why in the world would they vote
for for Cuomo? And did you see what uh
what um Mandani said in his victory
speech about Cuomo? I wish uh Mr. Quomo,
the best of luck in
>> uh private life, but I hope to never
utter his name again.
>> That's great.
>> Ouch.
>> Well, yeah. I mean, Andrew Cuomo did not
really um conduct an honorable campaign.
>> No, he didn't.
>> Um it was
>> it was it was an Islamophobic campaign
>> beneath him and his family name. Um it
was it was it was sad and tragic to
watch. I mean, so I mean, if I mean,
obviously, if the system like
manipulated the vote at all, obviously
they couldn't take it away from Nandani,
the the win was too big. It's a
landslide for people. Just I just want
to keep reminding people this was a
three or four person race. Uh this was
this was so when you get over 50% of the
vote in a three, four person race, it's
a landslide. You've kicked ass. um be
you know the day before the vote Cuomo's
at 24%.
And now suddenly he's at 42. Really?
Come on. Come on. 17%. That's after
Trump endorsed him, by the way. And that
only could have hurt him in New York
City. Uh you know, in something that
Cuomo knew because he said, "No, no, I
I'm good. I don't need it." And then
even Trump was like, "No, I'm not
really. It's okay." It was just a
speaking out of turn. Um, and then SE I
mean the only thing that would explain
it to me would be if Slee with
supporters saw that it he was going to
be, you know, washed out. They're like,
I'm not going to bother to wait in these
long lines. This was record turnout. 2
million votes in a city of uh just shy
of 8 million people.
>> Um,
>> you know, in an off-year election. I
mean, one of the ballot initiatives,
John, was I don't know how, by the way,
I have to look up how this did. one of
the ballot there were eight initiatives
yesterday and one of them was in New
York City. Should we move the the the um
the mayoral race to uh a presidential
election year because nobody votes in
the off-year mayoral election.
>> He set a record yesterday.
>> They set a record. It was a record
turnout. It was double double the number
of votes that turned out for uh Eric
Adams election two years four years ago.
>> That's correct. Yeah, exactly.
>> And this was like Yeah. You have to go
back to Mayor John Lindsay of the 1960s
to find similar numbers. Now, the You
might say, "Oh, the population of the
city is is bigger now." Actually, the
population of the city is a little
smaller.
>> So, um that's not really true. So I
wanted to ask you too if you don't mind.
Um Mandani's uh biggest uh vote vote
tallies were of course in uh in Queens
part parts of Queens and Manhattan.
So what was up with the Bronx? I mean I
guess I get Brooklyn
I guess.
But Brooklyn is actually more ethnically
mixed and racially mixed than Manhattan
is. So why were his numbers so strong in
Manhattan and in in far western Queens
than they were in areas that I would
just have have assumed that he would run
up the the numbers?
>> Well, I haven't had chance to study the
uh the uh precinct by precinct um
results which the New York Times just
published like right before we went on
the air. Um, and I'm going to look at
that because I always find those
fascinating. But certainly the Bronx
overall, first of all, a big section of
the Northwest Bronx is Riverdale,
>> right? Jewish white. Yeah.
>> And then um and then there's also a lot
of Latinos, right? Um, and Latinos often
are small C conservative, right? Or big
C conservative. Yeah. Um, so I'm
suspecting, but you know, AOC does okay
there, but
>> that's because she's uh
>> she went mainstream
>> and also she's she's Latina. I mean,
there's a there's um former Bronx
Burough President um Jose uh Ferrer runs
a political machine up there in the
Bronx and I suspect that his thumb is on
>> this um on this. And I think and I do
think some things change. I mean, I just
don't I think the system decided to give
Quuomo a more dignified loss on the on
the record just because I mean, I know
this is conspiratorial thinking and it's
speculation and I have no evidence for
it, but you know, it just it doesn't
seem right. Like, you know, you hit the
M all the polling hits Mani right on the
nose,
>> but like not you know, Cuomo suddenly
kicks major ass. I mean, you know, he
he'd lost by a lot less than we
expected. Um, so
>> have you had a chance I I looked and I
couldn't find it easily, so I just moved
on to something else. Have you had a
chance to look at the um lower level
races in New Jersey? I have no idea what
happened to New Jersey in the uh in the
legislature to look there. But it does
look it does look like a Democratic
sweep. It's a it's a repudiation I think
of Trump's style.
>> And you know I think if I were meeting
if I had if I had 10 minutes with
President Trump uh I would say listen
you know I care about the country so I
want you to succeed. If you succeed we
succeed. And I believe that
>> I do too. And I would say you've taken
on you're you you've fallen for a
typical pre secondter term presidential
mistake which is you're you're finding
satisfaction in foreign policy and
you're you took your eye off the ball of
why you're president. You ran on
domestic issues. You ran on the economy
and you've basically aside from the
tariffs haven't really done anything
about the economy and the tariffs are a
mixed bag to say the least. Right. and
and people are still the things that you
identified correctly about high prices
and low wages are still if anything
getting worse and uh and people see you
you know sending money to [__]
Argentina
>> right
>> and not here. So I mean I think I mean I
think this is partly that repudiation.
People don't like the ICE [__]
>> Even people who are anti-illegal
immigration, they don't like the way
this is being handled. the goons on the
streets of the city, the National Guard.
>> I went downtown yesterday afternoon to
have coffee with a friend and um and
there were two National Guardsmen in the
Farragut West Metro Station. Farragut
West, probably the single safest metro
station in the entire metro network.
And I and I as soon as I saw them at a
distance, I was like, "Don't say
anything. Don't say anything. Don't say
anything." And I walk up to them and I
said, "You guys should be ashamed of
yourselves." And I walked away. They
didn't say anything.
>> That's all I said.
>> Yeah. They didn't respond at all. Hey,
and I wanted to say this is apppropo of
nothing, but I thought people would get
a kick out of it. When I was on Rogan a
couple of weeks ago,
um, we somehow got on to the topic of,
uh, AI and I said I didn't like chat GPT
because it lied about me and it's it
just made up that I went to the
University of Maryland and to some grad
school in Belgium that I've never heard
of. And I told ChatGpt, "You're wrong."
And it says, "No, you're wrong." Right?
And um so I I was I told this story to
to Rogan and Rogan says, "Oh, we use
Perplexity here. They um are advertisers
on the show, but but for our own use
here at the studio, we use Perplexity."
And I said, "I'm going to start using
Perplexity."
Last night around like 10 o'clock, the
CEO of Perplexity sent me an email with
a lifetime subscription to Perplexity.
He said, "Thank you for the conversation
you had about Perplexity. Here's a link
for it's for Perplexity employees. It's
a free lifetime subscription to
Perplexity."
>> That's great. [laughter] I love that. So
now I'm going to be all about
Perplexity. [laughter]
>> All I have to check out Perplexity. I'm
like, you know, as you know, I'm I'm
banned on chat GPT. Yes. My personal
account is banned. I'm not allowed to
access. If you type in my name, it's
literally like a 1960s Star Trek episode
where the robot says does not compute.
Does not compute.
>> Ridiculous.
>> Literally if you don't believe me.
>> And it's and it all started because uh
same thing. They made up lies about me
like, "Oh, this contra, you know, they
took away my Pulitzer Prize. I never won
a Pulitzer Prize." Um, [laughter]
don't have it to give up. Um, this crazy
literary feud I supposedly had with
Scott Stantis.
>> Best friends. We've never had an
argument in our lives. Um, you know,
it's just bizarre. Oh my god. It just
makes [__] up. It It's, you know, they
call it hallucinating. It's not
hallucinating. It's just lying.
>> It's just lying. It's like Ridiculous.
Well, now it's going to be perplexity.
>> Yeah, Vick Vicki in Greece is asking uh
Vic in Greece is asking why am I banned?
Uh so I wrote a piece for the Wall
Street Journal about it and I and the
title which I didn't write was uh Chad
GPT lie me. Should I sue? And uh I I and
after that I got banned. So you know
that's why
>> jerks. Oh my god.
>> So, let's see. Um Bob channel says he
uses co-pilot. It makes a lot of
mistakes.
>> I don't know that one. I have one in my
doc that's called Comet.
I don't know. Is that perplexity? I
think perplexity is perplexity. Anyway,
I'm going to download it today. I'll let
you know how it goes.
>> What Cole Lebach wants to know, what do
we think about Giuliani saying New
Yorkers have forgotten in about 911?
Never. Giuliani is so drunk by 12:00
noon, he's already forgotten what he did
yesterday. So what honestly whatever
Giuliani has to say, I dismiss it as the
the the rantings of a crazy person.
>> Sorry, I'm a little bitter about
Giuliani.
>> Well, he he's a dick. Um I mean, anybody
who doesn't believe he seriously watch
Borat, too. I mean, guys,
>> he's got his hand down his pants because
he thinks he's gonna he's so gross. year
old.
>> Um, Phil 2082 has been uh kind of like
semi-trolling the feed, but I figure we
can address this. Um, he said, "Do we
honestly believe the leftist garbage
Mani is pushing will somehow magically
not result in millions murdered?"
Earlier in the feed, he was arguing that
communism inherently will result in
millions of people being killed.
>> Yeah, but but Mandani is not a
communist.
>> That's true. This is what I I I so many
>> socialist really.
>> Not really. I mean,
>> he's just a liberal.
>> He's a democratic socialist, which is
really just a a traditional liberal, a
>> it's Humphrey, it's John Lindsay. I
mean, what's happened here, right? Like
so what's kind of interesting and and
this might explain what happened to um
SWA is that the two parties have shifted
so far over to the right over the last
60 70 years that now in at least the New
York mayoral election what you really
have is Mandani who's basically John
Lindseay in the 1960s running against
Andrew Cuomo who's basically a
Republican from the 1960s like a silk
stocking upper east side Republican
politically.
Um, and then SWA is somewhere where I
don't know the John Burch Society like
would not have been elected, right?
>> Is he that conservative?
>> Well, he's I mean he's he's affiliated
kind of with MAGA world now.
>> Okay.
>> What is mainstream Republicanism now
would have been off the charts like like
Barry Goldwater would have been like
what the [__]
>> Oh yeah, I believe it. I believe it.
even near the end of his own lifetime,
Goldwater was coming around. Um,
Goldwater, I had I had very deep respect
for Barry Goldwater. When his
granddaughter came out to him, he became
one of the greatest champions of gay
rights on Capitol Hill.
>> Incredible.
>> And it's not early. I mean, you know, as
um Scott Stantis, by the way, who's
going to be filling in for you tomorrow
to co-host
>> Oh, thank you. here uh just for one day
um is uh he he always likes to quote
Goldwater saying like I don't care if
the guy in the foxhole in in the foxhole
next to me is straight I care if he can
shoot straight
>> shoot straight I remember that
>> and and he was a what a major general
Barry Goldwater in the reserves
>> he was either [laughter] Yeah he was
either a brigadier general or major
general in the army reserves
>> yeah I didn't know Mhm.
>> So was uh Jimmy Stewart, the actor. He
was a brigadier general.
>> Real real says, "Chat GPT angers me. I
wish I could find AI that isn't so
mainstream."
>> I know, right?
>> I like
>> I use it all the time.
>> I haven't used it,
>> but I've I've read other people, you
know, commenting about using it.
>> By the way, I I want I want to I want to
stand up for communism here. I don't
think that like calling for equal income
and wealth inherently results in having
to kill millions of people.
>> Right. Yeah. Agreed.
>> That certainly has happened. And I don't
think that and I think that had very
little to do with with wealth
redistribution and a lot more to do with
the authoritarian form of government
that was sort of using communism as a
cover like Mao and you know Stalin. I
mean Stalin didn't kill didn't kill all
those people to redistribute wealth.
some of them but not most. This was
about control.
>> Yeah, it was about control. Yes.
>> You know, in that sense, it's not about
it's not the e- I don't think the
economic system inherently results, but
I think every system results in, you
know, control. The need to control your
fellow human beings necessitates leaders
thinking that they have to kill some of
their fellow citizens.
>> Yes.
>> Um, agreed.
>> Let's see. Oh, Phil 2082 said,
"Yesterday we talked both talked about
getting EMDR therapy for PTSD.
The current VA wait time for veterans
for that is 12 months."
>> Are you kidding me?
>> I can't get it after three wars, Phil
says.
>> Oh my god. I'll tell you what, my um
insurance wouldn't cover it at the time,
so I paid for it out of pocket and it
was 700 bucks.
>> Yeah. My recommendation, Phil, I don't
obviously we don't know your financial
situation, but here's the thing. You
don't need a lot of sessions
>> to get to get some big [__] results.
>> No, I I had like four sessions and I was
I was good to go.
>> Three.
>> See?
>> Yeah. And like one's like a prep
session, so you might just need four.
>> I actually fell asleep in the first one.
I got so relaxed.
>> Yeah,
>> man. I cried so much. I mean, and I
don't really cry, you know. I'm one of
those people like I can't cry even when
I want to and then it's like I just like
disintegrated.
>> You know, it was great. [laughter]
>> See, my my my problem is murderous rage.
>> If I can back off from the murderous
rage, then I'm okay.
>> Oh, Fasmatas wants to know what it I
mean, I guess we should like not use uh
jargon. Um, you know,
>> oh, sorry. So, EMDR basically is based
um you might have heard of tapping, but
basically it's based on this theory that
um it's just it's just sort of like we
don't really know why it works, but we
know that it works. And basically, it's
kind of like a form of gentle hypnosis.
That's why I fell asleep. Basically,
you're focus like you're with a
therapist. You sit across from them and
they wave like usually they wave a stick
around and you and you and you uh and
you stare at it and you're asked to go
back to the thing that traumatized you
and and how you felt and what happened
and and the the person will prompt you
with some uh some cues and uh and and
we'll just sort of walk you through try
to take you back to that. And it's very
weird. It's like a primitive response
thing. It's sort of like when you pet
the, you know, you pet the back of a cat
right before its tail, it can't help but
arch up. They just do.
>> Yeah.
>> Sort of like that your your brain just
sort of responds to it that way. It's I
I recommend looking it up. It's, you
know, too common.
>> I agree. I agree. And I mentioned I did
that transcranial magnetic therapy where
you just put this uh it's this band of
magnets around your head and uh you have
to wet these two gauzy contact points
right here and it's attached to a
battery and you turn it on. You have to
have it on for 20 minutes. For the first
like minute, it makes your eyes go
completely blurry, you know, like like
you're shaking a TV and watching the TV
as it's shaking, that kind of thing. And
then it it stops
and then you just take it off after 20
minutes.
>> Um,
and I did that for a few weeks, worked
like a charm.
>> There's also these these wristbands that
you can buy that that they pulse on your
wrist. Um, [clears throat] and they're
like, yeah, like a hundred bucks. Um,
Frazzmataz just wants, and this is
important. I don't understand how you
can do EMDR if you're not a combat or
otherwise physical PTSD patient. How do
you get EMDR about your divorce? Anyway,
that's personal. Don't need to know. I
think it's important. Um, look, you can
get traum the short answer is you can
get trauma over all sorts of things um
that are not physical. Um yeah, you
know, and uh you know, for you know, in
in my case, I I did have PTSD over not
my own personal combat, but having been
in uh you know, in in a war in
Afghanistan as a journalist and uh
seeing a colleague of mine die. Um and
uh it was and I was diagnosed with that,
right? Um abusive childhood which can
involve physical abuse. But anyway, this
basically psychologists are very clear.
There's really kind of not much
difference in the effect between
physical and emotional and psychological
abuse. I mean, the effect is kind of the
same. I mean, forget the kind of. It is
the same. There's no difference.
>> It's the same. That's right.
>> You know, whether if your if your your
parent yelled at you, screamed at you
all throughout your childhood, and they
never laid a hand on you, it's no
different than if they had.
>> That's right.
Um, I want to thank uh uh Solon too uh
for his generosity. And he had a
question here that I just saw. Oh, I I
see. Am am I ever going to be on um on
uh the Rogan show with Mike Baker?
[laughter]
Um
probably not.
Probably [laughter] not.
The the truth is I have a manager now
who is uh she also represents well I
won't say who she represent she
represents some really high highle
people and um [snorts]
and uh
she told me that I'm more highly soughta
than than Mike Baker is. So why
legitimize Mike Baker,
>> you know? And and speaking about Bamante
too, Bamante is included in the in the
question. Um
>> Rogan Rogan will not have Bamante on the
show. Period. It will never happen.
He and his people were crystal clear
about that. There will be no Bamante on
that show. He's not a person that is who
is taken seriously.
Well, while we're on the topic of covert
[__] should we talk about Exxon?
>> Yeah, let's talk about Exxon, bastards.
>> So, this is crazy story. Um, it it
reminds me a little bit of the story of
the attorney who uh ended up being uh
sent to prison and uh subject to house
arrest for uh winning a huge uh $ 1.5
billion a damage award uh in favor of
indigenous people down in Bolivia
against Exxon Mobile. Um Stephen
Danziger, my my neighbor in Manhattan.
Um anyway, uh in fact, I was thinking
maybe I'm going to reach out to him and
see if he can come on the show.
>> That would be great.
>> Talk about this. Um but anyway, so it
turns out there's um basically Exxon
throughout the late 90s and throughout
the thes was uh bankrolling uh the Atlas
Network, which is a think tank down in
Latin America, uh basically doing
Spanish translations of climate denial
propaganda, uh like stuff by Fred
Singer, who's against the Kyoto Accord.
And um and basically it's just meant it
was meant to undermine the scientific
consensus that the that the planet is uh
going through rapid uh humancaused
climate change glo average global
warming.
>> I mean which is really the simplest
science in the world. Like if you own a
ever seen how a terrarium works it's
like third grade science. There's not
that much to it. And it used to be
mainstream until Ronald Reagan decided
to politicize climate change and the
envi and the and the environment
overall. So long story short, um you
know, this is kind of like how big
tobacco used to operate. Um you know,
paying scientists to to say that
cigarettes weren't dangerous or not that
dangerous or whatever. Um
so this all just came out. The Guardian
broke the story. Um, it's I mean it's
really gross and it's like very
revealing that like a lot of the
[__] that's out there kind of like
you know people felt it was legitimate
because they read stuff that sounded and
felt real as if it was from real
intelligent qualified intellectuals and
scientists but it was all [__]
>> Yeah. How do we I mean is there is there
anything we can do as a society to hold
companies accountable for for this kind
of propaganda?
>> No, not not when the Supreme Court
repeatedly sides with the companies. I
mean look at the look at the precedents.
U there are no good cases to point to.
The little guy always loses. It's like a
Stephen King novel that the good guy
always loses.
Terrible. Just terrible. Steven
Donsziger is is the the clearest example
of this. The guy is a freedom fighter.
Talk about talk about, you know, the
savior of the of the little guy, the
indigenous people of what was it? Uh,
Ecuador.
>> Bolivia.
>> Bolivia. Bolivia. And uh and an
administrative judge sentenced him to
prison. Ended up being house arrest. But
still, you know, the big polluting,
filthy, killing corporations always get
away with it, and they're going to keep
getting away with it until somebody
finally stands up, somebody in a
position of authority finally stands up
and says, "Enough of this."
>> Well, they have billions of dollars and
billions of dollars can always buy
congressmen and presidents and,
>> you know.
>> Yes.
>> That's the thing. When people say take
the money out of politics, that's
ridiculous.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Um,
>> well, you know what? What did it was
Citizens United. I mean, I'm I'm sure we
all agree. I I'm actually very sure we
all agree on Citizens United.
Corporations are not people, and
corporations should not be able to to
donate unlimited literally unlimited
amounts of money to political
candidates. It it it just completely
corrupts the system.
>> Yeah. No. Um, for sure. And you know,
other countries definitely know how to
handle that. Um,
>> yeah, I like Don Ziger. You know, he was
on the show that Michelle and I had
several times. Um, he would be great on
this show. We should have him soon.
[snorts]
>> By the way, um, do we have any thoughts
about this? This isn't this is a
curveball, so I apologize if you didn't
look at it. Any thoughts about that UPS
plane crash in uh in Kentucky?
>> You know, I think it was just one of
those things. They're saying now seven
dead and like 11 or was it nine now?
>> Yeah. I I think it was just one of those
things.
>> Awful.
>> We'll have to uh dig into it. Yeah. I
mean, people don't really spend you
know, we don't really think about how
many of those um you know jets are uh
you know have no windows. They're UPS.
They're FedEx.
>> All cargo.
>> A lot of cargo in the skies, right? And
not to mention the passenger planes are
also carrying mail. I think I mentioned
to you one time I had to fly I had to
fly from Seattle to
Gnome, Alaska with Gary Johnson and it
was a big like a 767. I was like what?
They have that many people flying to
Gnome, Alaska from Seattle to warrant a
767? I mean you take those to Europe and
back. Well, it turned out there were
only like 20 seats on the plane. all in
the back and all of the rest of the
plane was cargo. Everything was cargo.
>> Yeah, it's crazy.
>> Um, we should talk. Um, I do want to I
do want to like not let go about I do
want to a little thing about the mayoral
election and all all the elections
yesterday. I mean, we're now about to
see and this was the thumbnail today,
right? A war in the Democratic party,
right?
>> Absolutely. Yes. I mean, wouldn't the
right thing to do, the smart thing for
the DNC be to say, listen, we have
multiple approaches. Um, you know,
during Occupy Wall Street, we used to
say like different tactics for different
situations. Um, you know, democratic
socialism, look, is that a model that
can be replicated everywhere? No. But
can it be replicated uh for the mayor,
the mayor of Los Angeles and San
Francisco? Sure. You bet. Um and like or
Chicago or Boston, sure, Miami maybe. Um
and it's like uh similarly, you know,
but the corp so we're being told like
well we're already seeing efforts just
to to marginalize Mandani and say he's a
quantum singularity. New York City is
different. It's not like the rest of the
country. I remember always thinking when
people would say like that must be very
strange to live in New York City. It's
so different. And I would say, you know,
more people live in New York City than
anywhere else. So, actually, it's not
that strange if you think about it. You
know, like far far fewer people live in
small towns. And so, I was um so I'm
just think, you know, I'm just that's
going to be their talking point. New
York is weird. You know, that's that's
them. But, you know, clearly what the
Democrats nationally are doing hasn't
been working,
>> right?
>> So, I don't know. It'll just be
interesting. We know the war is a foot
and
>> see and and you and I both know that the
Democrats don't have the foggiest idea
what they're doing, right? So, are is
this is this going to be the party of
Abigail Spanberger or is it going to be
the party of Zoron Mandani or is it
going to be something in the middle or
are the Democrats just going to throw up
their hands again and say, "Oh, we don't
know what to do. Um, but you should vote
for us because we're not the other guy."
[snorts]
>> Yeah. I don't trust him. I don't trust
any of them. And even if even if the
right thing to do is to make the party
more in line with Zon Mandani and his
positions, I'm just saying if
what's to keep the DNC leadership from
just stealing the next presidential
nomination from somebody who is more in
line with Zon Manny than with Abigail
Spanberger?
I I don't trust them. We need we need
multiple parties in this country. Just
like we used to have as recently as a
hundred years ago, there were legitimate
viable parties. In in the 1968 election,
George Wallace won what, six, seven,
eight states.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We need we need third parties,
several of them.
>> I like this. Yeah, we do. Uh Freud 6624
is asking over on YouTube if we're
seeing a growing presence of more
radical positions in younger people,
particularly Gen Z, both right and left.
>> Good question.
>> It's a great question. Um I think we're
certainly seeing greater radicalization
across the board. Young people always
tend to have more extreme opinions
anyway, but I mean the right has been
really true. Young right wingers have
been really radicalized in by the
internet in recent in the last 10 years.
>> Yes.
>> And I think the same thing's been true.
I mean, yeah. I think the short answer
is Yeah.
>> Wow. Yeah.
>> So, I mean, that's also because we're in
a pre-revolutionary moment, you know.
>> Yeah. I wonder what Robbie would say
about that because he's young and he's
very right-wing.
>> He's not as young as you think, though.
He looks
>> How old do you think he is? I just
assumed he was about 30.
>> He's 48. YO
>> WHAT?
>> I know, [laughter]
>> Robbie. Kudos to you, man.
>> But clean living.
>> Wow. That's that pure air up there in
Montana.
>> Yeah, it's crazy.
Crazy. Oh my god.
>> Frazzmat says, "Mani promised not to
appoint a new police commissioner." Max
Blumenthal made a good point that the
NYPD is a state within a state and its
commission has an unusually has a
usually tight relationship with Israel.
That is true.
>> That is true. And and Max Blumenthal was
he hit that nail right on the head.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, I I agree with Fire Sig.
Using the term radical is ridiculous.
How about a Gen Z is seeing things for
what the environment represents? Yeah.
They're fatalistic, man. They they know
they've been handled a shitty [__]
you know, hand.
>> My son and I, my third son and I have
had this conversation a hundred times.
I'm going to go see him in a few days.
We're going to have this conversation
even more. Um, how does somebody in this
generation
afford a first home, for example, unless
you want to
>> possible?
>> Yeah, it's not it's not possible. Unless
you want to live out in the sticks
somewhere. uh you can't like he he knows
that he will never again live in
Arlington, Virginia. It's not possible.
I remember when I got back from
Pakistan, I had so much money from
overtime and danger pay and language
differential and post differential and
pdeium. I bought a house. I bought a
house, a little one. Um it it was 1,200
square feet on three floors. That's how
small it was. And I paid I still
remember I paid uh 347 for it. 347,000.
I sold it two years later for 721 and
now it's a million bucks.
A,200 square foot house. A million
dollar. And I remember my my ex and I at
the time
marveled over this Washington Post
article that and this was like I say 20
years ago that Arlington had sold its
first million dollar house. And I said,
can you imagine that? $1 million
for a house. It's just insane. Okay. Not
too long ago, 20 years. Well, now the
average home price in Arlington is 2
million.
And that's every house, the average. And
in my neighborhood, which is no nicer
than any other neighbor, it's just a
normal, you know, middle class, middle
neighborhood, the average is 3.2
million. I can't afford to live. I I I
have two housemates and we live in a
townhouse. Otherwise, I could never hope
to live here. What about my kids? My
kids grew up here and they'll never ever
be able to live in a place like this.
Something's got to be done.
>> Otherwise, we're headed for an economic
catastrophe where an entire generation
is cut out.
>> Yeah, I think we're already we're
already there. Um, by the way, Village
idiot um has a really good point here in
regarding third parties, regional
parties, successful healthy regional
parties like the old Democratic Farmer
Labor Party in the upper Midwest
>> and conservative versions too. And there
were others historically.
>> Um there was like the city party in
Philadelphia
>> um and uh stuff like that. Um,
>> yes,
>> there that that could
>> it's a really good point. It's vi it's
more viable, right? I mean, you can
start locally and then try to expand
regionally. Uh, but you get you get a
foot in the door.
>> Yeah. Um, village idiot says, "A house.
Who cares what's your local school look
like? No one cares. Privatize your
hospital. No one cares. Privatize
transport. Private. Wake up. It's
different in Arlington. The the schools
are absolutely magnificent, which is why
we moved here in the first place. It was
before we had children, but we wanted
our children to have access to Arlington
County schools. Um the hospital,
they've saved my life more than once. I
mean that quite literally. Um although
it is likely private. Transport is not
only public in Arlington. it it was free
for 5 years from COVID onward
and now they just implemented a flat $1
fee. You can go anywhere in Arlington
County, one buck.
So, it's unusual here. And this is a
place that's very very um where people
are very successful financially, but
they voted 77% for Barack Obama.
So,
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> Crazy. Um,
>> what are you seeing?
>> I'm looking at uh Well, well, sorry.
What am I I'm I'm looking at the uh uh
the the the chat. Phil 282 says uh
Weather Underground is 40 plus years
ago. It's all Antifa now, and it's just
the name for everyone pushing out more
terrorism. I think that's, you know,
that's [__] propaganda to be honest.
I mean, there just Antifa hardly exists.
It's, you know.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. I I have to agree. I I'm not a
believer that Antifa even is a thing. I
mean, people can put a mask on and call
themselves Antifa, but it's not
You can't like join Antifa. It's It just
doesn't It just doesn't exist.
>> No.
>> As an organization,
>> that would be totally right. Um All
right. So, let's talk a bit about um
Sean Duffy. He's the He's the Secretary
of Transportation.
>> Um he says that if the government
shutdown continues next week, starting
roughly Tuesday, um he's anticipating
having to shut down swads of airspace
over the United States due to a lack of
air traffic controllers. He says there's
um 3,000 they're 3,000 controllers
short. Um, and they're uh they have
already mass chaos. He describes it at
big airports like uh JFK and Newark um
and in right across the river from New
York City uh where already the lines are
getting really long. TSA is not uh is
short staffed. People are quitting or um
just sort of doing sickouts. Um and uh
he's think he's saying that like there's
going to be a meltdown well before
Thanksgiving. uh major travel weekend.
Um that's a major problem. Um is he
bullshitting or is this just uh the
Trump administration trying to pressure
Democrats?
>> Uh no, I think he's I think he's being
serious. I flew in from Spain a couple
of days ago, what um Sunday? And um
the lines getting through security were
ridiculous. I I passed them as I was
leaving. But I mean, there just weren't
enough TSA people processing travelers
through security, number one. But when I
was coming in through immigration,
I filled out the it's called MPC, the
mobile whatever, whatever.
>> Yeah. You know, on your phone.
>> I have that thing, too.
>> I don't know why everybody doesn't do
that because there's never a line. You
just blow right through. So anyway, the
immigration guy is just sitting like
this and he goes, "Look at the camera.
Welcome home." And I [laughter] just
just walk past and I'm in. That's it.
It's like, "Wow." It's cuz he's not
getting paid. So he doesn't give a [__]
[laughter]
>> What country?
>> I think this is bad. We're headed for
something bad. Last night at midnight,
>> it's not even LIKE WE'RE BROKE. IT'S NOT
EVEN LIKE WE'RE like we're like Molly
and our natural resource is rocks,
>> right? No, there's plenty of money.
>> We just we're just choosing not to use
it. Like this like the snap stuff.
>> We just don't We just We got the money.
We just don't want to use it.
>> We don't want to use it. Last night at
midnight, this became the uh longest
shutdown in American history.
>> Yes.
>> And there's no end in sight.
>> None.
>> No. And and I do think it's really
important. And I talked a little bit
about this on tmi yesterday, but I think
it's really important to understand for
the Democrats there is this is
existential. Republicans don't
understand it, right? Like if Democrats
sign the continuing resolution now then
the then you know they're Republicans
are totally lying when they say, "Oh,
we'll talk about subsidies for
Obamacare." No, they won't.
>> No,
>> they won't sign it. No. And then next
year, not only Obamacare collapses
because, you know, that's propping up
the entire system. By the way, it'll
drag down private insurance, too,
because Obamacare subsidizes the private
insurance sector, too, for people who
have like quote unquote normal jobs at
big corporations and stuff. So, the
whole health care system tumbles off a
cliff, right? Which probably would
benefit Democrats, but to their credit,
they don't want that. But it it would be
denying them their only major le
legislative achievement in 30 years,
right? So lit literally they would have
nothing to say. What's the last thing
you guys did? NAFTA. Oh, don't want to
be bragging about that. Welfare reform.
Don't want to be bragging about that.
The crime bill under Biden and uh and
you know and Clinton in the N. Don't
want to be bragging about that. You have
to go back to like Jimmy Carter. Did he
he has no major legislative achievement.
You have to go back to like the war on
poverty to find a major democratic
legislative achievement. So, you know,
they can't let this go. It's literally
like you're not even a party anymore if
they let it go. That's all they have.
It's it's literally the legacy of the
modern Democratic party.
>> Yeah.
>> And if they lose it, they have nothing.
You're right.
>> And I'm not a fan of the ACA. I think it
sucks.
>> No. Nor am I. I I'm I'm telling you
because I live it. It sucks. It sucks.
>> Yes.
It it's like but the thing is the you
know it's one of those things that like
as shitty as it is uh it's going to be
it's only going to get worse. Uh Craig
Dance is asking where does funding for
ICE come from? It just comes from the
federal budget.
>> Yep.
>> Phil [snorts] is insisting about Antifa.
They have cells and international
cooperation.
The people just putting on masks also
call themselves of this.
>> All right. Well, you know, if that's
true, can we see some evidence, please?
>> Yeah, please lay it out. I I'm perfectly
happy to change my position.
>> Me, too.
>> If I see the evidence.
>> Me, too. Uh, Nicholas Franco is asking,
"What is the Conservative Party of New
York?"
>> That's a good question.
>> So, there
>> is is it a legit party still?
>> Not really. uh it's sort of like I mean
if you look at the so New York City uh
New York state actually has there's the
old there's working families party uh
which is a left-leaning party and
there's the conservative party which is
self-evident and basically when you go
to vote the the line for the working
families is almost identical to the line
for the Democrats they just take cut and
paste the name of the Democrat over to
working families
>> I if I vote for a Democrat, I will vote
for the working families line just so
that it supports them. But the truth is
it's a shell. It's a husk. And then over
on the same thing on the conservative
side, the conservative party tends not
to have its own candidates.
>> Oh, really? So they just take whatever
the Republicans do and
>> Yeah, it's it is a shame. Yeah, it's not
really real.
I remember the 1980 Senate race in New
York um when Jacob Javitz was suffering
from Lug Garri's disease but decided to
run for reelection in a in a crazy
Republican year. He was a liberal
Republican.
He lost the Republican nomination to
Alamato and then but he still stayed on
the ballot as the liberal party
candidate. So he split the vote with the
Democrat and New York was cursed with El
Damato for like three terms.
Yeah, the I have a Yeah. Alamato. God, I
I remember him very well. But he was the
pothole he was the pothole senator.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yes, he was. That's how he kept getting
reelected.
>> He believed in that [__] which, you
know, not not wrong,
>> right?
>> Um trying to think if there's any last
minute any any last minute stuff we have
to talk about. Um we're going to have a
lot more data on the election tomorrow.
Um, you know, so it'll be uh Yeah, here
we go. Jonathan Morris says, "The
working families is basically the Warren
wing of the New York City Democratic
Party,
>> except that they don't they hardly don't
they hardly have any of their own
candidates.
>> That's a shame.
That's a shame because they know they're
going to make it onto the ballot and so
that's 80% of the battle right there.
Take
>> seriously a waste." Mhm.
>> I think, you know, the vibe I get is
that basically they are um they're
planning to uh they're planning to just
do um there it's like a placeholder.
We're going to do become a real party
soon, but we're not really ready right
now. We're like, you know, like next
time, but we just keep we'll just keep
the ballot access. We'll just use the
Democratic thing. And then they, you
know, they they're out to brunch and
that's that's how it is every single
time.
>> Yeah. What a waste.
>> It is.
>> What a waste.
>> Well, John, you're going to be out
tomorrow. Um,
>> yes, I'm going to be out
and I'll be back the day after.
>> We We'll see you again on Friday. Um,
thanks everybody for joining us. We are
here Monday through Friday. Uh, that is
uh Mon at 9:00 a.m. Eastern time.
Please, please, please go over to this
apparently only works in the United
States. givesgo.comwestglacaming.
We'll that's how you're going to help us
keep Robbie on the show. We'll we'll
keep you up to date. Um sort of provide
a therm thermometer about how much money
we're we have so far and how close we
are to our thousand per month goal here.
Um it's still the beginning of the
month, but we'd like to get this out of
the way so we can stop talking about it
and just do the show. Robbie's due to be
back with us a week from Monday. So,
we're looking forward to that. He's he's
doing his two week final notice. Uh
John, good luck tomorrow.
>> Thanks, buddy.
>> And uh looking forward to to uh seeing
you again on Friday. Scott Stantis will
be joining and Phil sitting in the
John's seat trying to fill fill his big
shoes. Um he and and uh please stay
tuned for the TMI show with Ted Roller,
Manila Chan coming up right after this.
Thanks everybody and take care.
Pleasure.
[music]